Dave and I are here today to talk
about Patreon, I'll start.
We exchanged many emails
with all the people in our business
network and no one is happy with things
which happen so we are
think of other options and
checked SubscribeStar but it seems
that PayPal decided to stop funding them
so the transition to an alternative platform,
an alternative commercial platform that
is out of our control, out of our control it doesn't make it sustainable,
so Dave, why don't you explain what we talked about today.
Yes, well I think so first
it should be made clear to everyone how much
is significant what happened to Carl
Benjamin, Sargon of Akkad,
it doesn't matter what you think of him or whether you agree with him or anything like that,
but to ban him for something he did
van Patreon's platform,
which wasn't even on his channel,
because of the word he said and used
against the alternative right or neo-Nazis
or whatever you want to call them,
it is a huge shift in the boundaries of what is acceptable
and now we can have various discussions and we have had them,
where the boundaries should be and whether they should exist at all but
is the fact that this man was thrown out just like that,
no questions, no warnings,
and this is just an extension
everything we talked about.
Also, given that
that he did not violate Patreon's rules,
the ones they set up and about which you are
talked to Conte as well as about the fact
that it won't happen and that Patreon didn't answer this well ...
Well, look, Jack Conte came in
my studio, in my house and said,
he uttered a phrase I had never heard before,
maybe you are, 'manifest observable behavior'
you haven't heard this phrase before, have you?
alone that this is just something I missed, well
now of course 'manifest observable behavior, MOB mob (crowd), I think,
that's it, how nice, but
but the point is that it had to be
regarding conduct and then in their Terms
usage must also be related to something that is happening
on the platform so it is on every border
of what should be permissible Patreon scheduled and
they put us in a position where, you know, I said,
I called you last Saturday when this is
it really took off and I told you to Patreon
makes up about 65 to 70% of my income, I now have a firm
with full-time, part-time employees,
and I was actually thinking of deleting it right away,
and no normal person would, no businessman
I wouldn't do that and I took a lot of risks
in the past, you know, before I was on Patreon
I was on Ora TV with my producer and director,
we all quit, lost health insurance, all that
to get to Patreon means I like to take risks
but then I realized, well, we need to have some plan
and that’s actually why we do this. Well, we would go
and faster but, well,
i opened an account on SubscribeStar but I never did
to the end adjusted in part because
SubscribeStar seemed to start decaying almost immediately,
they attacked them, and the same was not clear,
I have read their Terms of Use and
and it was not clear whether we would just go again
find in an identical situation,
and you can only make so many mistakes before
but as these mistakes become fatal,
so we came to one seriously and
stable solution, I worked
on it for months, literally months,
I have been working on the system for six months now
which will allow authors and
to other people who publicly discuss intellectual topics
to connect more efficiently
with its readers, viewers,
and listeners, and
this week it occurred to me that, along with some
change can be achieved
exactly what we hope he can achieve
so we'll try it
do as quickly as possible, establish a system
on a subscription model similar to Patreon's,
there will be a lot of additional functionalities that I don't want to talk about now
and I don't want to promise too much but the system is,
because the system is new
but we will try to run it
as soon as possible,
we have a lot of people who are interested,
hypothetically interested in changing the platform
for contribution payments. Dave and I.
we plan to do this very seriously
as soon as we find a smart way,
so ... And you know, by the way,
one of the interesting things we didn’t talk about
but I guess we had similar experiences, the amount of emails
which I received and of course tweets and everything else but
mostly e-mails from developers, investors,
ordinary people, engineers, I think
everyone says that's it, because you know what the problems are
with free speech,
you don’t want to swing too soon, before you realize that
the problem reached a critical mass, but then
you will most likely swing too late, the lines will be like that
far from being maybe out of it and that's why
I think this is so interesting because, Carl
is five or six years ago,
when I started to see what was going on in the left and of course
the whole thing about free speech, everyone told me you have to talk
with Sargon of Akkad, it is the man who
was a step ahead of all this ...
Sargon was great and helped me a lot
when they just started attacking me,
you know he is a brave man, and
what Patreon did to him was a real mistake
And, like I said everyone in our network are strong
upset about it, we exchange emails
with some 30 to 40 people
and, as Dave said earlier, we wanted to shoot this video today
to inform all of you we are talking to, yes
we haven't given up on this,
indeed, people
trying to find ways to stop this from happening as well
and we have a good plan and
we will try to implement it as soon as possible so
I would ask all of you who are listening to this to be
reasonably patient, I guess we'll need it
about a week to a month
to sort this all out, we'll do our best to finish something
next week, hopefully before Christmas, and if
we fail, it’s because
with things like this they are always possible
technical problems that arise unforeseen
but I don't want you to have the impression that
we take this lightly or retreat
and not to look for a permanent one
an alternative because we’re looking for it, and I think we can make it
a better alternative and that is our plan.
Yes, that’s exactly what I wanted to say, and I would add more
that we were waiting for the right moment, you know,
we watched this door slowly close for all of us,
whether it's Twitter or Facebook,
when they ban, when they secretly ban, the processing of earnings, and everything else
and we take this very seriously, and of course
you know that Jordan, who works harder than anyone else in this world,
somehow managed and partly to build a platform
during this year in spite of everything else.
I knew, we knew this
lurking in the background and will become a problem
and Dave, you spent a lot of time talking to
investors and developers o
creating alternatives to these platforms that,
they seem to be increasingly arbitrarily enacted
advantage without any hesitation,
but it is not easy. People want to
to say something is enough now,
and as i mentioned on the live stream the other day but
I watched my Patreon collapse, I lost an eye
600 sponsors, about $ 5,000 a month,
but, surprisingly, that actually inspired me
because I watched ... I agree ...
Well on the one hand people send me
emails and say they give up patronage and are annoyed,
that it is not up to me and that they want to support me, on the other hand
my business side tells me it's not good but
you know we'll work it out ...
I'm the same, I've lost a thousand subscribers and I feel the same way,
as if telling Patreon to carry on
and you know, it's not good for me financially
sides although not some big one
disaster currently, they are taking up
for the right thing and encourage us,
or let's say they encourage someone else to do something about it, so ...
I like what you said, if you
we can ask you to be reasonably patient, we are talking to
to all possible people and some impossible ones,
and we'll fix this, we will.
Or at least we will give
do our best to fix it, there will be some obstacles along the way
because now we have to speed up this process
so we will consider this a beta version but
at least we hope to provide you with an easy way
to switch to a new subscription service
soon
and thank you all for your patience,
and constant support and attention
and on your opinions
and reactions to all this,
we appreciate it a lot and I would say it helps us to
we have motivation
to continue working.
You know, having all these subscribers on Patreon
is certainly one of the reasons that
I am trying to put this Youtube channel
on, I wouldn't say first place, because he had to make room for
this tour lectures, but is very high on the list of priorities.
Sure, and it gives us a lot
the flexibility to do various things also gave me the opportunity
to join you on this tour and therefore I am
incredibly honored and grateful to everyone ...
Jordan, see you for
a few days in West Palm Beach,
and I'm taking you to dinner.
Great,
I found a good restaurant, I'm looking forward to meeting you ...
Great, see you ... Because the tour
we continue in California,
three locations in California in January and
then two in Australia and New Zealand,
and we will add some more, I give myself to Seoul and
Singapore, maybe the Philippines,
we still have a lot of things planned ...
Will there be anything on the moon?
Well not yet but I know
Elona Muska pa ...
Good ...
Talk to you soon and keep up the good content.
Great. Hi.